Hello and welcome to the introduction video for the course "Foundation of Data Science", in the second semester.
And of course, this course builds on top of the stuff that you would have covered in the first semester in the "Introduction to Data Science" course.
So there are two things I guess I wanted to talk about in comparison to the course you did last semester.
In the course last semester you covered the basics of how to use code for data and how to use the libraries,
how to use Python, and a little bit about how to draw conclusions in the presence of randomness,
permutation tests and different ways of using permutation to draw conclusions about what you see in data in the real world,
assuming some degree of randomness. So we're going to move on in two different ways.
And the first way I want to talk about is the approach to data, and that's really centred on the project.
So I'm going to talk about the project all the time during this course.
The project is the absolute beating heart of the "Foundations of Data science course.
So what's going to happen is that, in the first few weeks,
I'm going to send you all away to try and find data that you want to analyse, data you're really, really interested in.
So there's an enormous amount of data out there available on the web, all sorts of very interesting real data sets.
That, I want you to find one and I want you to try and think of things you'd like to find out from the data - conclusions
you might like to draw, relationships you might like to try and find.
And of course, at the same time, gather a team, because this is a group project.
And it's absolutely central to the whole idea here that, you learn to take the skills
you've learnt last semester and start applying them in collaboration together,
working together on data analysis. So that's one aspect of the course - a different approach to data analysis -
Really going for a serious, big, difficult data analysis problem.
And the second thing is the extra stuff going to cover. So you're going to build on where we started and ended in the semester last semester.
So as you remember, at the end of last semester, we were just beginning to cover the idea of looking at relationships between different measures.
So, for example, we were looking at the relationship between the Packed Cell Volume measure in blood tests in
kidney patients and the corresponding measure for haemoglobin in those same kidney patients.
And we were trying to see if we could find a good and convincing straight line relationship between these these two sets of numbers.
That that is simple regression. And we'll go into that a bit more and think about how we would find a good straight line,
how we would find a convincing slope for the line in an intercept.
And talk about correlation, what the correspondence is to regression.
Now, in doing that, we'll come across this fantastic technique called numerical optimisation,
which is something that Python and many other languages can do for you.
It's a standard technique in computing, which gives us a very neat and automated way of finding the kind of things we're interested in here.
So, for example, we want to find a good straight line. What do you mean by good straight line?
We mean one that minimises the sum of squares of the errors.
And we can go and ask the computer to find us that parameter, search around and find the line which does that for us.
And that's that's numerical optimisation.
And it's a fundamental technique in and doing a lot of the stuff that we want to do with these kind of inference techniques.
And it turns out this extends very simply and obviously to how we would do more interesting and complicated things.
So, for example, we were trying to predict, as you remember,
the haemoglobin concentration from the Packed Cell Volume concentrations in the same patients.
But maybe we've got more than one thing measured in the patient that we want to use to predict.
So we've got the Packed Cell Volume to predict the haemoglobin. We've got something else as well.
We want to see what we can use them both at the same time to predict the haemoglobin. That's multiple regression.
We're using two measures to predict the thing we're interested in.
And that falls out, in fact, neatly and gracefully from the simple regression techniques you've already learnt.
And then we're going to move on to more stuff. So we're gonna think about prediction a bit more.
We're going to think about classification. So putting things into groups, giving them labels.
So, for example, kidney patients
Does a patient who's come into hospital have chronic disease or do they not have chronic kidney disease.
We have some measures we've taken in the blood. Can we use those measures to predict whether they have kidney disease or not?
And this is a machine learning problem, often called classification problem.
And you build up your own basic machine learning models, classification models and learn how to decide whether they're good models or not.
And then finally, in the stuff we'll cover, we'll go on to how you work out whether the parameters that you found
- so, for example, the slope in the straight line or or even just the mean of some data in a sample -
how good are those parameters? How how much can we trust them? How representative are they from the population from which that sample has been drawn?
So, for example, if we have a mean, is that mean likely to be close to the mean of the population or could it be quite a long way away?
And this is the problem of confidence intervals. And in doing that will actually also cover how to think about using prior information.
And this is Bayes Theorem. So I hope you enjoy this semester.
You'll be doing a lot of independent stuff. As I say, the project will be absolutely central.
And I think you'll find you will start to get real experience in real data analysis while also covering these extra
and I think you'll find, interesting and important topics.
So, welcome to the course.